<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>TheAbsnt</title>
    <link>https://theabsnt.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on TheAbsnt</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>© TheAbsnt</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 09:35:05 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://theabsnt.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Zero2Auto: Ch03-Practical Analysis Challenge (Part-III)</title>
      <link>https://theabsnt.github.io/posts/z2ach03/part03/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 09:35:05 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theabsnt.github.io/posts/z2ach03/part03/</guid>
      <description>Yo Yo Yo!!! What&amp;rsquo;s up guys? Hope ya all having a nice time, Welcom back! In this last part of analysing challenge binary from Z2A: Ch03(Practical Analysis). We gonna take look at mighty capabilities this binary hiding within it, So, let&amp;rsquo;s get started ..
INSIDE main():    fig1. decompiled main() of stage03     All this stage does is display a message box and exit
   fig2.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zero2Auto: Ch03-Practical Analysis Challenge (Part-II)</title>
      <link>https://theabsnt.github.io/posts/z2ach03/part02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 15:46:46 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theabsnt.github.io/posts/z2ach03/part02/</guid>
      <description>Yo Yo! ! Welcome back, in the part-II of analysing the challenge binary from Z2A: Ch03(Practical Analysis).
 I encourage you to follow this writeup along with your analysis.
 We gonna take a thorough look into second payload extracted from .rsrc section and injected into another process of stage01(main_bin.exe). So, let&amp;rsquo;s get started from the main of this stage..
Stage02: Extracted from .rsrc section of stage01 INSIDE main():    fig1.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zero2Auto: Ch03-Practical Analysis Challenge (Part-I)</title>
      <link>https://theabsnt.github.io/posts/z2ach03/part01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 15:25:42 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theabsnt.github.io/posts/z2ach03/part01/</guid>
      <description>Yo! What is up guys, This post is walktrough of challenge binary(Chapter 03: Practical Analysis) from Zero2Auto course. This challenge tries to get you comfortable with reversing topics by covering variety of topics, to name a few, API hashing, anti-debugging, malware authors fav. PEB manipulation, process injection, thread context hijacking, basic unpacking, crypto&amp;hellip; and so on, that&amp;rsquo;s why i wanted to cover this binary
In this Part-I of this series we&amp;rsquo;ll walkthrough the base binary(stage01) ie.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>https://theabsnt.github.io/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Aug 2023 15:22:27 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://theabsnt.github.io/about/</guid>
      <description>Who Am I? My name is Sunil. I am a security researcher(heh!!.. such a cool name!!), on my way to keep learning and sharpening my reversing skills, some of the certificates and courses i&amp;rsquo;m doing/completed are PMAT, Zero2Auto: The Ultimate Malware Reverse Engineering, OST2 courses.
What You Can Expect Here? You can expect posts related to malware reversing, exploring the mechanics behind malwares
Thanks of visiting, I hope you enjoy your stay and got some value off of it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
